-相信这个人可不明智 我能搞定他
-Trusting this man is not a good idea. I can handle him.
时间变异管理局已经裁剪过这家伙很多次了 他们各不相同
The TVA has pruned a lotta these guys, and no two are alike.
你们都是时间犯
LOKI: You're all Variants!
时间守护者并没有创造你们 他们把你们从时间线上绑架了
The Time-Keepers didn't create you. They kidnapped you from the timeline.
前情提要
你们两个造成的关连事件
MOBIUS: The nexus event you caused,
不管是什么关系 会让这个地方崩溃
whatever that connection is, can bring this whole place down.
好吧 你想知道真相吗？
RENSLAYER: Fine. You want the truth?
我在试着保护你
I'm trying to protect you.
像我们这样的友谊并不常见
Friendship like ours is uncommon.
你知道让我选 我想去哪里吗？
You know where I'd go if I could go anywhere?
从哪里来我就该回哪里去
Wherever it is I'm really from.
对 在时间变异管理局之前我生活的地方
Yeah, wherever I had a life before the TVA came along.
裁剪掉他
-Prune him.
时间守护者夺走了你们的人生
The Time-Keepers took your lives from you.
你们都是时间犯
You're Variants.
咱们是一样的
We're the same.
没有灵魂的机器人
SYLVIE: Mindless androids.
那是谁创造了时间变异管理局？
LOKI: Then who created the TVA?
希尔维 我有话要对你说
Sylvie, I have to tell you something.
把你知道的一切都告诉我
You're gonna tell me everything.
漫威影业
这是什么地方？我们在哪？你们是谁？
LOKI: What is this place? Where are we? Who are you?
这里是虚空 那是艾利奥斯 而我们是它的午餐 赶紧吧
This is The Void. That's Alioth. And we're his lunch. Come on!
洛基
把你的时间控制器给我
Give me your TemPad.
-时间变异管理局背后是谁在操控？ 我也不知道
-Who's really behind the TVA? I'm as in the dark as you are.
可悲的洛斯蕾尔法官 你所认定的现实都被颠覆了
Poor Judge Renslayer. Your whole reality's been destroyed.
跟我说说 知道真相的感觉如何？
Tell me, how does it feel to be on the other side of it?
也就这样了 是不是？
This is it, isn't it?
这就是你在窃取我人生后 带我来的地方
This is where you dragged me after you stole my life.
-也会是你人生被夺走最合适的地方 要是我说洛基还没死呢？
-A fitting place, then, to take yours. And what if I said Loki wasn't dead?
至少应该还没有
Not yet, anyway.
-你在说谎 也许吧
-I'd say you were lying. Maybe.
-也许咱们想要的东西是一样的 他怎么可能还活着？
-Or maybe we want the same thing. How is he still alive?
以及我们能通过救他来接近 时间变异管理局背后的主使吗？
And how will saving him get us closer to who's really behind the TVA?
这事比较复杂
It's complicated.
-告诉你这些我心甘情愿 为什么？
-I'm telling you this willingly. Why?
因为我想知道谁在掌控这一切
Because I wanna know who's at the top of this.
我想知道谁欺骗了我
I want to know who lied to me.
当我们裁剪一个分支现实的时候
When we prune a branched reality,
我们不可能毁灭掉所有的一切
it's impossible to destroy all of its matter.
所以我们把它移动到时间线上的某个地方 让它停止发展
So we move it to a place on the timeline where it won't continue growing.
基本上来说 时间线分支并没有重置
Basically, the branched timeline isn't reset.
-而是被转移了 转移去了哪里？
-It's transferred. To where?
时间尽头的虚空
A void at the end of time.
在那里 所有的存在互相碰撞
Where every instance of existence collides at the same point
然后停止发展
and simply stops.
为什么？
Why?
我也不知道
I don't know.
规则里面说 时间的尽头仍然在书写中
The dogma states that the end of time is still being written,
时间守护者会把它变成乌托邦
that the Time-Keepers are transforming it into utopia.
说得好听 真是唬人啊
That's nice. Super believable.
不管真实原因是什么…
Whatever the real reason. . .
从来没有什么能从那里回来
nothing ever comes back from there.
如果你相信我 我能帮你
I can help you if you trust me.
我建议咱们歇一下 我有无数个问题想问
I suggest we take a breather, so I can ask several thousand questions.
-不想死就赶紧走 好吧 但是你的计划是什么？
-Gotta keep moving so we don't die. Okay, but what's your plan?
-别死 好吧 还有呢？
-Don't die. Okay, but beyond that?
-别死 这算不上计划
-Don't die. That's not a plan.
这只是求生欲 作为洛基 就应该永远有计划…
It's a general demand of living. If you're Lokis, you should always have. . .
有没有谁能给我解释一下 到底是怎么回事？
Will someone please explain to me what the hell is going on?
过去的几天里 我一直非常非常地努力
Look, it's been a very, very, very trying past few days.
或许是几个月？我都不知道 自从纽约事件后到底过了多久
Months? I don't even know how long it's been since New York.
我只知道我被裁剪了 醒来就在这里了
All I know is, I got pruned and I woke up here,
还有一群跟我身份一样的时间犯围着我 以及一只短吻鳄
and now I'm surrounded by Variants of myself, plus an alligator,
可悲的是我都不觉得奇怪
which sadly I didn't find all that strange.
现在我们既不知道在逃避什么鬼 也不知道该往什么鬼地方逃
And now we're running from God knows what to God knows where.
而我需要想办法回到时间变异管理局去
When I need to be trying to find a way back to the TVA.
别叫唤了 你会引来艾里奥斯的
Stop wailing or you will signal Alioth.
你说那个天上的怪物？
You mean the monster in the sky?
谢谢
Thank you.
这里是时间变异管理局的垃圾场
This is the place where the TVA dumps its rubbish,
所有被裁剪的东西都在这里
everything they prune.
然后艾里奥斯
And Alioth,
确保这些东西有来无回
he ensures none of it ever returns.
它是个有生命的风暴 吞噬物质和能量
BOASTFUL LOKI: It's a living tempest that consumes matter and energy.
他们把所有分支现实扔到这 然后被立刻吞噬…
They send entire branched realities here that are devoured instant--
我们就像在鲨鱼缸里 艾里奥斯就是鲨鱼
We're in a shark tank. Alioth is the shark.
并没有什么鳄鱼缸
Oh, there's no such thing as an alligator tank.
而且这就是个比喻而已 他跟我们其他人一样 太敏感了
Besides, it's a better metaphor. He's overly sensitive like the rest of us.
等等
Hang on,
-那玩意也是洛基？ 是啊
-that thing's a Loki too? Oh, yes.
好吧 没什么不能接受的 为什么有这么多个你们？
Okay, fine. Willing to accept that. Why are there so many of you?
因为洛基总能活下来 这可是咱们的强项
Because Lokis survive. That's just what we do.
-太棒了 那咱们怎么逃出去？ 我们逃不出去
-Great. So how do we escape? We don't.
我们都是被时间变异管理局逮捕 然后裁剪掉的 和你一样
All of us were arrested by the TVA and pruned, just like you.
而且我们都在制定各种无谓的计划 也和你一样
And just like you, we all stood around making bad plans that went nowhere.
咱们可以使用时间控制器啊
But we could use a TemPad.
逃跑的救命稻草 没错
Oh, the one thing that could get us out of here, yes.
应该到处都有吧 是不是？
They're all over the place, right, guys?
好吧 那如果制造出一个关连事件呢？
Fine. What about causing a nexus event?
时间变异管理局根本不在乎这里发生了什么
The TVA doesn't care what happens here.
-总能做点什么吧 有
-Surely there's something to do. There is.
活下去 这是唯一的办法 从过去到现在都一样
Survive. That's all there is. All there ever was.
话说完了 咱们走吧
KID LOKI: We're done talking. Let's go.
你想怎样随便吧
Just do what you want.
好吧 等等 等等
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
你为什么戴着角？你对那个小孩言听计从
Why do you wear the horns? You let a child command you.
你可得尊重那个孩子
You'll do well to respect the boy.
-这是他的王国 对
-This is his kingdom. LOKI: Right.
你的关连事件是什么 国王陛下？
What was your nexus event, Your Majesty?
我杀了索尔
I killed Thor.
话说回来 你为什么这么急着 回时间变异管理局？
So, why did you want to return to the TVA so badly, anyway?
你把光荣的使命留在那里了？
You leave your glorious purpose there?
差不多吧
Something like that.
时间小姐 我需要远程接入
RENSLAYER: Miss Minutes, I need you to remote access
存档中的一些机密文件
a series of restricted files from the archives.
天啊 关于什么的？
MISS MINUTES: Ooh, doggy! On what?
时间的起始 时间变异管理局的建立
RENSLAYER: The beginning of time. The founding of the TVA.
-马上 等等
-MISS MINUTES: Right away. Wait.
-看看时间的尽头怎么样？ 那就是虚空而已
-What about the end of time? It's just a void.
如果虚空不是尽头呢？ 如果还有虚空以外的东西呢？
What if The Void isn't the end? What if there's something beyond it?
我就是躲在末日的阴影下 才逃离了时间变异管理局的视线
Hiding in the shadow of apocalypses obscured me from the TVA
因为我在那里不能创造分支 对不对？
because I couldn't create a diverging branch there, right?
所以如果这些都仍然在书写中 发生的任何事都会是一条新的时间线
So if all of this is still being written, whatever happens is just a new timeline.
在那里不可能出现关连事件
It would be impossible to start a nexus event there.
-你可能完全无法被发现 就是这样
-You could be completely undetectable. That's it.
-那是他们唯一能去的地方 那我们怎么穿越虚空呢？
-That's the only place they could be. So how do we get past The Void?
这是不可能的
It's impossible.
时间控制器无法定位 没有目的地
There's nothing for the TemPad to lock onto, no destination.
那我们就穿过它看看
Then we go through it.
-这是自杀 那我觉得留着你也没什么用了
-That's suicide. Then I guess my need for you has passed.
等等 试试虚空飞船怎么样？
Wait. What about The Void spacecraft?
对 那个原型机
Yes, the prototype.
太好了 我来找文件
Great. I'll get the file.
那艘飞船是用来应对现世虚空的
It's a spaceship designed to withstand the temporal void.
它能把我们带到时间的尽头
It could take us to the end of time.
-找到洛基 找到幕后的主使
-Find Loki. Find the man behind the curtain.
-然后杀了他 齐心协力
-And kill him. Together.
时间小姐 这艘时间飞船的文件在哪里？
Miss Minutes, where are the files on this timecraft?
正在搜索 亲爱的
MISS MINUTES: Still lookin', hon.
还没找到吗？
Nothing?
它埋藏得很深
Hmm. Buried pretty deep.
那是高度机密 我可能都没有权限
It's highly restricted. I might not even have clearance.
不 我觉得你有 如果它真实存在的话
Oh, no, I think you would. If it's real.
还要多久？
How long?
随时都有可能
Any second now.
上啊 快点
GUARD: Go! Go! Go! Move it!
-你受伤了吗？ 我没事 但是她拿了我的时间控制器
-You hurt? I'm fine, but she took my TemPad.
希尔维？你不会还想逃跑吧？
Sylvie? Not thinking of going on the run, are you?
我们知道你藏在哪
We know where you hide.
我们早晚会抓住你
Sooner or later, we'll catch you.
你肯定已经筋疲力尽了
It must be so exhausting.
我承认刚才有那么一瞬间 我相信了你
I'll admit you had me fooled there for a minute.
也有可能你说的是真心话
Or did you get a little real?
洛斯蕾尔法官真的觉得 被她心爱的时间变异管理局背叛了吗？
Did Judge Renslayer really feel betrayed by her beloved TVA?
要不然你出来 咱们好好聊聊？
Why don't you come back out and we can talk about it?
没问题 让其他人退下 咱们自己解决
Sure. Just tell everyone else to piss off and we can settle this between us.
我接受
Works for me.
你不是还说要去抓幕后主使吗？
What happened to finding the man behind the curtain?
我告诉你 举起双手出来
Tell you what. You come out with your hands up
我就把你放到时间循环里
and I'll put you in a time loop.
也让你少受点罪
Something not so bad.
你可以不断重温那些美好的回忆
You can live out your days in a good memory.
你有美好的回忆吗？
Do you have any good memories?
其实只有一个
Just one, really.
-她自我裁剪了 很好
-She self-pruned. Good.
那她也就完蛋了
Then she's dead, too.
洛克西酒 上等黑皮诺
在我征服了美国队长和钢铁侠以后
So, after I vanquished Captain America and Iron Man,
我拿到了我的奖赏 全部六颗无限原石
I claimed my prize, all six Infinity Stones.
那只短吻鳄在咆哮着说 〝骗子〞
That's alligator for growling and saying "liar" at the same time.
至少我的关连事件不是吃错了邻居的猫
At least my nexus event wasn't eating the wrong neighbor's cat.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Hey, hey, hey.
-讲讲你的故事 洛基 我的？
-Tell them your story, Loki. Me?
不会有人想听的
Nobody wants to hear about that.
其实我还挺想听的
I would, actually.
我就一直在想 因为我…
Um. . . It's just I've been wondering, because I'm. . .
我们本来该死掉的 是不是？
Well, we're supposed to die, right?
灭霸在诸神的黄昏后杀了我们
Thanos kills us after Ragnarok.
灭霸？
Thanos?
在我的时间线里
In my timeline,
一切都进行得很正常 我的一生都很正常
everything proceeded correctly, my entire life,
直到灭霸袭击了我们的飞船
until Thanos attacked our ship.
你没试着去刺杀他吗？
So, you didn't try to stab him?
当然没有
Certainly not.
我无意冒犯 朋友
Take no offense, my friends,
但是在洛基的法术面前 兵刃一文不值
but blades are worthless in the face of a Loki sorcery.
它们会阻碍我们的魔法潜力
They stunt our magical potential.
-但是它们看上去很厉害 是的
-But they look awesome. CLASSIC LOKI: Oh, yes.
特别是当你被掐住脖子 它们掉在地上的时候
Especially when they clatter to the ground just before your neck is snapped.
我制造了一个非常逼真的自己的投影 连灭霸都被骗过了
I cast a projection of myself so real, even the Mad Titan believed it.
然后我在一堆尸体里装死
Then hid as inanimate debris.
伪造了死亡以后 我就在宇宙中游荡
After I faked my death, I simply drifted in space.
远离索尔 远离一切
Away from Thor, away from everything.
我思考关于宇宙的一切 思考我应在的位置
Thought about the universe and my place in it,
然后我突然明白了 我所到之处
and it occurred to me that everywhere I went,
只会带去痛苦
only pain followed.
所以我就把自己从等式里抹掉了
So I removed myself from the equation,
我在一个偏远的星球落脚 独自一人 离群索居
landed on a remote planet and stayed there in isolation, in solitude
这样过了很久很久
for a long, long time.
时间变异管理局怎么找到你的？
How did the TVA find you?
我有点寂寞了
I got lonely.
说老实话 我想我哥哥了
To tell you the truth, I missed my brother,
我在想 他会不会在思念我 有没有人会思念我
and I wondered if he missed me, if anybody else did.
但就在我刚刚要离开那颗星球的时候
But as soon as I took my first steps to getting off the planet,
时间变异管理局就来了
the TVA arrived.
因为 亲爱的朋友 咱们只能扮演一个角色
Because we, my friends, have but one part to play,
流放之神
the God of Outcasts.
除此之外没有了
Nothing more.
流放之神
The God of Outcasts.
-我要走了 去哪？
-I'm going. Going where?
从这里出去 从虚空出去 回到时间变异管理局去
Out of this place, out of The Void, back to the TVA.
咱们既擅长生存 又擅长逃跑
We're as good at escaping as we are at surviving.
所以咱们机会很大
That gives me a decent chance.
-你哪个也干不好 你会被干掉的 那我也认了
-You won't do either, you'll be murdered. Well, so be it.
-那就是我本来的宿命 你与众不同
-That was my destiny to begin with. You're different.
-为什么？ 我没什么不一样的 你明白吗？
-Why? No, I'm not, you see?
我和你们一样 真的 我和你们所有人都一样
I'm the same, really. I'm the same as all of you.
你们有谁遇到过女性的时间犯吗？
Have any of you met a woman Variant of us?
-听上去很可怕 她确实挺可怕
-Sounds terrifying. Oh, she is.
但这就是她吸引人的地方
But that's kind of what's great about her.
她才是与众不同的
She's different.
她不是企图接管时间变异管理局 而是要推翻它
She's not trying to take over the TVA, she's trying to take it down.
她需要我
And she needs me.
你说因为艾里奥斯 咱们只能困在这
Now, you said Alioth is what keeps us here.
你说它是有生命的 你说它是条鲨鱼
You said it's a living thing. You said it's a shark.
那么如果它有生命 它就会死亡
Well, if it lives, it dies.
所以我要去杀了那条鲨鱼
So I'm gonna kill the shark.
我要杀了艾里奥斯 我需要你们的帮助
I'm gonna kill Alioth, and I could use all the help I can get.
太棒了 宝贝 太搞笑了
Yeah, baby. Yeah.
-一群怪物 太搞笑了
-Monsters. CLASSIC LOKI: Oh, yeah.
你好 你是我们中的哪一个？
Ah. Hello, which one of us are you?
这简直是噩梦
This is a nightmare.
是你
SYLVIE: You.
把门关上 咱们还没脱险呢
Shut the door, we still got a situation here.
就这么随便上陌生人的车 你可得小心点
You should be careful just jumping into a stranger's car like that.
-当心 我看见了 我看见了
-Watch out! I see it, I see it.
-真的吗？你直接就撞过去了 天啊 你真的和你们一模一样
-Really? You're driving right towards it. God, you really are one of you.
等等
Hang on.
洛基 竞选总统
你这个混蛋 你这是引狼入室
You bastard! You led the wolves to our door.
我们认为蛇比狼更贴切
We prefer snakes to wolves.
这些我都干掉过 它们的死法没什么区别
I've eaten both. They die just the same.
抱歉 我的陛下
Apologies, my liege.
我背叛了你 现在我是国王了
I betrayed you, and now, I'm king.
说到这件事吧…
About that. . .
-你不是认真的吧 拜托
-You can't be serious. Come on.
-你想要什么？ 我不是在讨价还价
-What did you expect? That was not the bargain!
我给你提供了我们的位置 你得给我们庇护和供给
I gave you our location. In exchange for shelter and supplies,
给我你的军队 我去夺取王位
you give me your army and I take the throne.
好吧
PRESIDENT LOKI: Ah, yes.
这交易不怎么样
Not so good a bargain.
那这个怎么样？ 军队是我的 王位也是我的
How about this one? My army, my throne?
说到这件事吧
About that.
你们这些愚蠢的下贱东西 为什么要这么做？
Why you beef-witted, half-faced scrubs.
-咱们说好的 看在老天的份上
-We had a deal! For God's sake.
这里为什么会有只短吻鳄？
Why the hell is there an alligator in here?
他是个洛基
ALL: He's a Loki!
为了光荣的使命
BOASTFUL LOKI: Glorious purpose!
来这边
Come on.
进来 洛基
Take that, Loki!
该死 一群禽兽！
Damn it! Animals, animals!
我们撒谎 我们欺骗
We lie and we cheat,
我们杀害了每个相信我们的人 为的是什么？
we cut the throat of every person who trusts us, and for what?
权力 光荣的权力 光荣的使命
Power. Glorious power. Glorious purpose!
我们不能改变
We cannot change.
我们就是坏蛋 每个版本都是 永远如此
We're broken, every version of us. Forever.
无论什么时候 如果有哪个 企图改邪归正
And whenever one of us dares try to fix themselves,
他们就会被送到这来送死
they're sent here to die.
这就是我为什么得从这出去
That's why I need to get out of here.
除非时间变异管理局被干掉 否则什么也改变不了
Nothing can change until the TVA is stopped.
-你相信她吗？ 她是我唯一相信的人
-And you trust her? She's the only one I do trust.
而此时此刻 我认为她是我们 干掉时间变异管理局唯一的机会
And right now, I believe she's our only chance of stopping the TVA.
这对我就够了
That's good enough for me.
好吧 好吧 我们帮你
Okay, okay. We'll help you.
但是接近艾里奥斯就是送死
But approaching Alioth is a death sentence.
我们会帮你接近它 但是也就到此为止了
We'll get you to it, but that's as far as we go.
一直以来 我真的认为我们都是好人
All that time, I really believed we were the good guys.
消除所有的现实 让小女孩无父无母
Annihilating entire realities, orphaning little girls,
真是经典的英雄事迹
classic hero stuff.
我想 如果为了结果可以不择手段
Well, I guess when you think the ends justify the means,
就没有什么是你不能做的了
there's not much you won't do.
而且你也没少消除东西
By the way, you did some annihilating too.
-我那是迫不得已 没错 我也是
-I did what I had to do. Yeah, so did I.
你像只猎狗一样追杀我
You hunted me like a dog.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry about that.
当我裁剪自己的时候 我觉得也许能找到洛基
When I pruned myself, I thought I might be able to find Loki.
那个风暴 那个东西 可能已经抓住他了
That storm, that thing, it's likely already got him.
你真的这么认为吗？
You really believe that?
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
现在唯一重要的事就是从这出去
The only thing that matters now is getting out of here
然后找到幕后的主使
and finding out who's behind all of this.
好 我们该怎么做？
Great. How do we do that?
我们需要掉头
We turn around.
掉头？回去找那团愤怒的乌云？
Turn around? What, and go back to the angry cloud?
对 我觉得那就是答案所在
Yeah. I think it might be the answer.
我们要回去找它
We're going back to it.
我必须得说 和那团庞然大物面对面 感觉有点糟糕
CLASSIC LOKI: I have to say, it feels odd walking toward the gargantuan creature.
你有行动的计划吗？
Do you have a plan of action?
冲进去 找到它的心脏或者大脑什么的
Get inside, find its heart or brain or whatever,
-然后 你知道的 动手 我的意思是…
-and then, you know, do it in. KID LOKI: I mean. . .
计划简单 不代表计划不行
Just because it's not complicated doesn't mean it's bad.
也不代表它就可行
It also doesn't mean it's good.
看 他表示赞同
See? He's on board.
他那是在祈祷 他觉得我们都要死了
He's praying. He thinks we're going to die.
所有人准备战斗
SAILOR: All hands to battle stations!
艾里奥斯和其它动物一样
Alioth is like any animal.
他会先去追逐那些大型的猎物
He'll go after the big meal first.
在它忙于那些的时候 我们就可以潜到它背后 然后…
And while he's busy with that, we can sneak around the back and. . .
开火
Fire!
好吧
Okay.
也许我们…
Maybe we, uh. . .
应该再好好想想 是不是？
think a bit more about this, huh?
有辆车
Car.
-什么？ 在那边
-What? Along the horizon.
是坏事吗？
LOKI: Is that bad?
一般都是食人族的强盗
KID LOKI: Well, usually means cannibalistic marauders
或者是食人族的海盗
or cannibalistic pirates.
真不错
Delightful.
他们在放慢速度
Now they're slowing down.
-他们在干什么？ 保持警惕
-What are they doing? Just stay on guard.
希尔维
Sylvie.
我不理解 他到底是懦弱还是勇敢
I don't understand. Is he a coward or was he being brave?
-我也不太确定 来吧
-I'm not too sure. Come on.
你还活着
You're alive.
发生什么了？你还好吗？
What happened? You okay?
莫比乌斯
Mobius!
-你们怎么… 我们觉得你可能需要援助
-How did you. . . We thought you could do with some backup.
不 等等 等等 这些是我的朋友
Oh, no, wait, wait, wait, these are my friends.
好吧 他们是…我该怎么说好呢？
Well, they're, um. . . How best to put this?
这是咱们的孩子版 这是咱们的未来版
Us as a child, us in the future,
这是咱们的短吻鳄版
and us as an alligator.
最好别去挑战它
It's best not to question it.
在这随便扔块石头 砸到的都是洛基
You throw a rock out here, you hit a Loki.
所以你也在追逐那个巨大的乌云怪物？
So you're all after the giant cloud monster, too, then?
我们还没决定怎么杀掉它 但是…
Well, we haven't decided how we're going to kill it, but. . .
-再说一遍？杀掉它？ 对 我们要杀掉艾里奥斯
-Come again? Kill it? Yes, we're gonna kill Alioth.
天啊 那是你的计划
Oh, my God. That was your plan.
-对 然后你们就这么接受了？
-Yeah. And you went along with it?
-我有我的疑虑 可能不太安全
-KID LOKI: I had my doubts. Probably unsafe.
好吧 那你的计划是什么？
All right, well, what's your plan, then?
我觉得我们要寻找的人 就在虚空之外时间的尽头
I think the person we're after is beyond The Void at the end of time.
如果他们真的在那
And if they are,
这个东西就是守卫着唯一入口的看门狗
that thing is just their guard dog protecting the only way in.
好吧 那我们怎么绕过这只看门狗？
Okay, so, um, how do we get past the guard dog?
我要附身在它身上
I'm gonna enchant it.
-那太疯狂了吧？ 那还要怎么样？
-That's insane, right? As insane as what?
-一刀一刀把乌云砍死？ 听着
-Paper-cutting a cloud to death? Listen,
-我来这时间比你长 我要附身在它身上
-I've been down here longer than you. . . I'm going to enchant it.
她很自信
She's pretty confident.
你们出去吧
Leave us.
为什么把我关在这里？
Why am I locked in here?
你放走了那个时间犯
You freed the Variant.
-你背叛了时间变异管理局 背叛？
-You were disloyal to the TVA. Disloyal?
-你觉得能逃脱惩罚吗？ 我背叛谁了？
-Did you think you'd escape punishment? Disloyal to who?
你在时间守护者的房间里 他们不是真实的
You were in the Time-Keepers' chambers. They weren't real.
那又能改变什么？
And why does that change anything?
那改变了一切
That changes everything!
人们需要知道真相
The people need to know the truth.
不 时间变异管理局需要稳定
No, the TVA needs stability.
在我们弄清楚怎么回事之前 它就必须要这样
And until we figure out what's going on, that is what it will get.
所以你得把一切告诉我
So you need to tell me everything.
你到底想要从我这得到什么？
What exactly do you want from me?
你和那个时间犯有联系
You had a link with the Variant.
我需要你告诉我她的动机
I want you to tell me what drives her.
她的动机就是复仇
Revenge drives her.
杀死时间守护者
Killing the Time-Keepers.
但是结果他们是假的 你不会忘了吧
But they turned out to be fake, in case you forgot.
所以她要去寻找创造他们的人
So she'll be searching for whomever created them.
这根本不是为了保护时间变异管理局 是不是？
This isn't about protecting the TVA at all, is it?
你就是想找到幕后的主使
You just want to find whoever is behind all of this, too.
你永远也找不到他们
You'll never find them.
至少不会比她先找到
Not before she does.
为什么？
And why is that?
你只是想找到
You only want it.
她是非找到不可
She needs it.
你好啊
Hey, y'all.
我需要所有时间变异管理局创立的文件
I need all the files on the founding of the TVA.
时间起始之后的一切
Everything from the beginning of time.
这个要求可有点难办
Well, that's a mighty tall order.
这个地方的缔造者正身处险境
Whoever created this place is in danger.
我得找到他们
I need to find them.
收到 立即行动 长官
Okay. Right away, ma'am.
你真的不记得他了吗？
CLASSIC LOKI: You really don't remember him?
我的意思是 时间变异管理局 逮捕了很多洛基
MOBIUS: I mean, the TVA arrested a lot of Lokis,
但是 不 我不记得有条短吻鳄
but, no, I don't remember an alligator.
而且 谁说他是个洛基的时间犯？
I mean, who's to say he's even a Loki Variant?
他是绿的 对不对？
He is green, isn't he?
我不知道 他可能在撒谎
I don't know, he could be lying.
隐姓埋名啊 当然 那只会让他更像是个洛基
The long con. Of course, that just makes him more likely to be a Loki.
你们这些家伙总是环环相扣的 这一点我很欣赏
It's always the game within the game with you guys, which I respect.
莫比乌斯
KID LOKI: Mobius,
假设你能回到时间变异管理局
assuming you do get back to the TVA,
你到底会去做什么？
what exactly are you getting yourself into?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我想让人们知道真相
I'd like to let people know the truth.
那么做的话 你就背叛了
So just like that, you're turning on the very thing
你为之奉献毕生的东西
you devoted your life to.
改变永远不晚
Well, it's never too late to change.
我希望他们知道他们在做什么
I hope they know what they're doing.
莫比乌斯没那么坏
Mobius isn't so bad.
也没那么好
Or so good.
我觉得这就是我们合得来的原因
I think that's why we get along.
他很关心你
He cares about you.
有点冷
-It's cold. Mmm-hmm.
如果你愿意的话 我可以给你变一个
I could conjure one for you, if you like.
我说 你还不如给我变一件新的外衣
You could conjure me a new outfit.
你可不知道这件有多不舒服
You have no idea how uncomfortable something like this is.
所以…
So. . .
关于莫比乌斯和他的理论…
Mobius and his theory about. . .
对 对 关于我们的关连事件
Right, right. About our nexus event.
-都是胡说 对吧？ 绝对是 肯定是 我是说…
-Total rubbish, right? Absolutely. Of course. I mean. . .
我并不觉得那个时刻有什么不好
I don't mean that it wasn't a nice moment.
对 那个时刻棒极了 非常好
No, it was great. It was really nice.
听上去像是又一个 时间变异管理局的谎言
It just sounds like another TVA lie.
百分之百 我觉得肯定是
A hundred percent. I mean, totally. Yeah.
我不知道该怎么处理
I don't know how to do this.
我甚至都不知道咱们在干什么
I don't even know what we're doing.
我没有朋友
I don't have friends.
我没有…
I don't have. . .
任何人在身边
anyone.
好吧…
Well. . .
你有更重要的事要做 对吗？
there are more important things, right?
是吗？对 比如推翻时间变异管理局
Right? Yeah. Like bringing down the TVA.
甚至是拯救宇宙
Saving the universe, even.
不用这么夸张 但是 算是吧
Well, there's no need to be dramatic, but, yeah, kind of.
这不是很舒服
It's not very snuggly.
-好吧 这是桌布吗？
Okay. Is it a tablecloth?
不 这是个毯子
No, it's a blanket.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
My pleasure.
我怎么能确定 在最后的时刻 你不会背叛我？
How do I know that, in the final moments, you won't betray me?
听着 希尔维 我…
Listen, Sylvie, I. . .
我背叛了所有爱过我的人
I betrayed everyone who ever loved me.
我背叛了我的父亲 我的哥哥…
I betrayed my father, my brother. . .
还有我的家园
my home.
我知道我的所作所为
I know what I did.
而且我知道为什么要那么做
And I know why I did it.
那已经不是现在的我了
And that's not who I am anymore.
好吗？
Okay?
我不会让你失望的
I won't let you down.
你确定吗？
You sure?
因为如果我们成功了 时间变异管理局不在了
'Cause if we make it, and the TVA is gone,
就会有一条时间线交给你来主宰
there might be a timeline for you to rule.
那我总算可以满足了
Ah. And then I'd finally be happy.
那你呢？
What about you?
这一切结束以后 你要去做什么？
What will you do when this is all over?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不知道
I don't know either.
也许
Maybe. . .
也许我们可以…
Maybe we could figure it out. . .
一起弄明白
together.
也许吧
Maybe.
好吧 下一步怎么做？
Okay, so what's the next move?
我们要推翻时间变异管理局
SYLVIE: The TVA needs to be brought down.
我们不知道是谁创造了它 也不知道他们在哪里
We don't know who created it or where they are,
但是那个东西知道
but that thing out there does.
之前它攻击我的时候 我和它连接了
When it hit me earlier, I linked to it.
时间很短 但是那一瞬间我看到了
It was brief, but I caught a glimpse of something,
如果足够接近 我就能附身在它身上
and I think if I can get close enough to it, I can enchant it,
这样就能找出真正的幕后主使
and it's gonna take me to whoever's behind all of this.
我要留下来
I'm staying.
-洛基 我不知道能不能成功 你去 我就去
-Loki, I don't know if this is gonna work. You go, I go.
快要出现了 伙计们 分支就在那里
It's happening, guys. The branch will be right out there.
我会替你向洛斯蕾尔问好的
MOBIUS: I'll give your regards to Renslayer.
请务必把我的问候带到
Oh, please do.
你们想从这出去吗？
You boys want a ticket out of here?
什么？不 我们要留在这里
What? No. We're staying here.
这是我们的家
This is our home.
你们确定吗？那艾里奥斯呢？
Are you sure? What about Alioth?
我们已经活了这么久了 我们知道该怎么做
We've survived this long. We know what we're doing.
洛基 你的旅途上需要这个
Loki, you're gonna need this on your journey.
拿着吧
Go on.
祝你们好运
CLASSIC LOKI: Good luck.
希望你们能得偿所望
I hope you find what you're looking for.
看来你最后还是脱身了
Looks like you got away in the end.
我一贯如此
I always do.
回到时间变异管理局以后 你要干什么？
What will you do at the TVA?
把它烧成灰烬
Burn it to the ground.
感谢你的星星之火
Thanks for the spark.
回头见 洛基
Well, see you later, Loki.
谢谢你 我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
你是我的最爱
You're my favorite.
分支出现的时候 就会吸引艾里奥斯的注意力
SYLVIE: When a branch appears, Alioth will focus on it.
那就是我附身的机会
That's when I'll enchant it.
如果我们没有时间等待分支出现呢？
What if we don't have time to wait for a branch?
咱们得分散它的注意力
We'll have to cause a distraction.
来啊 抓我啊
Come and get me!
不 来这边
LOKI: No! This way!
来抓我啊
Come and get me!
不 不
No! No!
他是怎么做到的？
How is he doing that?
我觉得我们比想象的更强大
I think we're stronger than we realize.
上吧
Go!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我们要附身在它身上
SYLVIE: We're gonna enchant it.
我不知道怎么做
LOKI: I don't know how.
你知道
SYLVIE: You do.
因为咱们是一样的
Because we're the same!
这是光荣的使命
Glorious purpose!
睁开眼吧
Open your eyes.
根据漫威漫画改编
漫威影业出品
洛基
字幕翻译： 虫二